Meng Chieh Lee

Email: meng.chieh.lee@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lee-mengchieh
Phone: 857-423-0388 Boston, MA

Github: https://github.com/jedi0605

PROFILE

Software Engineer at eASPNet data center with over seven years of experience developing software using C# .NET and Python. Led company team in developing CI/CD procedures for the production of robust and easily maintained code. Main focus: automatic laaS environment deployment, monitoring, backup, and disaster recovery services; helping companies to transform from data centers to cloud service providers.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Programing Languages: C#, .NET , Python, MS-SQL, Javascript, Powershell, Redis, Extis 6.0
- Dev Tools/Frameworks: Vmware, Git, NUinit, Jenkins, GitLab, Selenium, Flask
- Platform: Docker, AzureAD, RabbitMQ, InfluxDb, Terraform
- Dev Principles: REST, CI/CD, Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

eASPNet, Software Engineer

May 2016 - Present

- B2B Sales Platform
 - Achieved a cost savings of \$90,000 per year and reduced deployment time by 70% by developing an automated system that replaced VMware Orchestrator's dependencies.
 - Generating 40% of income by providing a high RESTful web API using Python, Flask, MS-SQL, Redis, and a load balancer to third parties.
 - Reduced human error through: leading development team in communication with Sales Department to determine requirements;
 using .net MVC, MS-SQL, Reddit to develop B2B laaS sales platform; importing VMware Orchestrator services; assisting
 Maintenance and Operations Department's fully automated deployment of laaS.
 - Increased network services revenue by 10% by designing a network traffic monitoring system which can handle a QPS of 160,000 by using InfluxDB, ntopng.
 - Fully automated UI testing with Selenium test scripts.
- Enhanced Website Performance
 - Reduced average case processing time by 30% by integrating ERP platform and creating mobile web services
 - Increase website performance 15% by migrating from .net Framework to Core architecture using YARP Proxy
- B2C Sales Platform
 - Integrated VMware Vcd and Operation information, allowing users to access laaS Disaster Recovery status on single website whilst providing periodic services settings including backup, snapshot, and power status
 - Integrated Veeam and VMware services using C# to create B2C sales platform, allowing end users to purchase laaS, Load
 Balancer, Backup, and disaster recovery services
 - Accepted nsx-t Load Balancer information through Web Api, and Auto-Scaling of laaS service using Terraform
- Enhanced Product Delivery Services
 - Led the team that reduced testing time and resource demand during Release, Staging, and Testing by creating CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, GitLab, Selenium, Nunit, and Docker

GCCA - Software Engineer

Mar 2013 - May 2016

- Virtualization System
 - Used Selenium to automate testing scripts for web applications, reducing manual testing time by 70%
 - Reduced setup time by 50% by developing automated Hyper-V HA cluster settings using Powershell and C#
 - Designed and built web app for users to create local Hyper-V/VMware laaS virtualization environment
- Video Doorbell
 - Created chat service using RabbitMQ, C#, and Wit Ai, allowing users to communicate with smart doorbell through text, control
 door lock, and register users
 - Implemented facial recognition module via OpenCV, allowing users to unlock a smart doorbell

EDUCATION

Medical Informatics, Master Degree, Tzu Chi University 2010 - 2012

Medical Informatics, Bachelor Degree, Tzu Chi University 2006 - 2010

Relevant Coursework: Introduction to Programming, Software Engineering, Algorithms and Data Structures, Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION Able to work in the US without visa sponsorship